Finding Aid for the Abraham Abbott Kaplan Papers LSC.1023
UCLA Library Special Collections
Abraham Abbott Kaplan papers
1947-1966
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1023
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Abraham Abbott Kaplan (1912-1980) was a lecturer in labor economics, author of several books, and an arbitrator in industrial disputes. He also worked for the UCLA Institute of Industrial Relations extension service, the UC University Extension, the Department of Theater Arts, Suny Purchase, and the UCLA Graduate School of Management. The collection consists of transcripts and printed materials relating to labor disputes, mainly in Southern California, in which Abbott Kaplan acted as an arbitrator.
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Professor Abbott Kaplan, 1967.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729563606533
Biography
Kaplan was born on January 12, 1912 in New York City; BS and MA in history, and Ph.D in adult education from Columbia University; B.J.A. from the Jewish Theological Seminary; became high school teacher, principal, then director of adult education for the Springfield, Massachusetts public school system; became lecturer in labor economics and head of the UCLA Institute of Industrial Relations extension service in 1946; then served as assistant director and associate director until 1957; worked as associate director, director, and statewide associate dean of UC University Extension in 1966, while serving as professor of adult education in the UCLA School of Education; with William Melnitz, founded UCLA's professional theater group; became associate dean and professor of theater arts; became president of Suny Purchase in 1967; at 65 returned to UCLA to join the Graduate School of Management as a visiting professor; was frequently an arbitrator in industrial disputes; author of several books, including Making grievances procedures work: the Southern California experience (1950) and Study-discussion in the liberal arts (1960); he died on July 13, 1980.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of transcripts and printed materials relating to labor disputes, mainly in Southern California, in which UCLA Professor Abbott Kaplan acted as arbitrator. Industrial disputes (listed alphabetically in the finding aid) include Douglas Aircraft and the IAMAW, California Electric power and IBEW, the Ferro corporation and the Allied appliance workers, and Union Steel Company and the U.S.W.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
1947-58 (Box 1).
1960-65 (Box 2).
1965-66 (Box 3).
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Arbitrators, industrial -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Kaplan, Abraham Abbott, 1912- --Archives.; University of California (System). University Extension--Faculty -- Archives; University of California, Los Angeles. Institute of Industrial Relations--Officials and employees -- Archives
- Alphabetical List of Arbitration Cases
  - Adel Precision Products - International Association of Machinists, Precision Lodge, no.1600., April 10, 1956. (Box 1)
  - Aircraft Bold Company - U.A.W., 683., March 3, 1953. (Box 1)
  - Airtek Dynamics, Incorporated - U.A.W., 509., February 8, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Associated General Contractors (Contracting engineers company) - Southern California district council of laborers., October 10, 1966. (Box 3)
  - Baldwin Extruded Products, Incorporated - United Rubber, cork, linoleum, and Plastic workers of American International Union, 141., December 2, 1964. (Box 2)
  - California Electric Power - I.B.E.W., October 1952. (Box 1)
  - California Electric Power Company, Riverside - I.B.E.W., 47., June 1953. (Box 1)
  - Cannon Electric - U.A.W., 811., April 30, 1958. (Box 1)
  - Clougherty Packing Company - Butchers union, 563., April 2, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Columbia Pictures - Office employees international, 174., January 29, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Craft Master - local no.123 & local no.691., May 5, 1958. (Box 1)
  - Crown Upholstery Company - United furniture workers., February 1953. (Box 1)
  - Crown Upholstery Company - United furniture workers., April 20, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Crown Upholstery Company - United furniture workers., May 24, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Crown Upholstery Company - United furniture workers., June 29, 1953. (Box 1)
  - Crown Upholstery Company - United furniture workers., August 17, 1953. (Box 1)
  - Douglas Aircraft, Long Beach - United Automobile, aerospace, and agricultural implement workers, 148., February 3, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Douglas Aircraft - I.A.M.A.W., district lodge 720., November 30, 1966. (Box 3)
  - Douglas Aircraft, Santa Monica - I.A.M.A.W., lodge 1578., May 19, 1965. (Box 3)
  - Douglas missile and space systems division, Huntington Beach - I.A.M.A.W., lodge 1578., November 16, 1965. (Box 3)
  - Douglas Aircraft, Santa Monica - I.A.M.A.W., lodge 1578., July 13, 1966. (Box 3)
  - The Ferro Corporation, San Francisco - Allied appliance workers, local 127., March 9, 1966. (Box 3)
  - General Cable Corporation - United electrical, radio, and machine workers of America, 1421., January 25, 1955. (Box 1)
  - General Cable Corporation - United electrical, radio, and machine workers of America, 1421., July 21, 1958. (Box 1)
  - Harbor Furniture Manufacturing Company - Furniture workers, 576., January 26, 1954. (Box 1)
  - Harbor Furniture Manufacturing Company - Furniture workers, 576., February 23, 1955. (Box 1)
  - Harmon Packing Company - International union of operating engineers, 63., June 15, 1953. (Box 1)
  - Herco Foundry Incorporated - United steel workers., September 9, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Holga Metal - I.A.W., 1600., November 12, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Holmes and Narver, Incorporated, Las Vegas, Nevada - I.U.O.E., July 11, 1966. (Box 3)
  - Isenberg & Son, Furniture Manufacturers - Furniture workers, 500., October 3, 1963. (Box 2)
  - Lerner Handbag - International fur and leather workers, 213., April 1, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Lynwood Bakery Company - Bakery and confectionery workers, 31., August 25, 1949. (Box 1)
  - Magnetic Research Corporation - U.E.R.M.W., 1421., September 13, 1955. (Box 1)
  - Montebello Meat Company - Butcher union, 563., March 1 & 17, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Northrop Aircraft - C.W. Frields., February 19, 1960. (Box 2)
  - Pacific Coast Borax Company - International chemical workers, 40, & 85., September 3, 1953. (Box 1)
  - Reynolds Electrical and Engineering Company - Culinary workers, 226., August 30, 1966. (Box 3)
  - R.C. Can Company - U.E.R.M.W., 1421., March 16, 1966. (Box 3)
  - Safeway stores - meat cutters, 421., December 1947. (Box 1)
  - Screen Directors Guild - I.M.P.P.A., September 1948. (Box 1)
  - Southern California general contractors (Casner construction company) - Southern California district council of laborers, 652., October 10, 1966. (Box 3)
  - Southern California Master Labor Agreements., Notebook. (Box 3)
  - Superior Recording - U.E.W., October 5, 1961. (Box 2)
  - Sydney Bag Company - International fur and leather workers, 213., January 23, 1952. (Box 1)
  - Tanner Motor Livery, limited - Dairy employees, Teamsters, 166., January 8, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Transfer and Storage industry comm. - Teamsters, 631., May 11, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Union Steel Company - U.S.W., September 9, 1954. (Box 1)
  - U.S. borax and chemical Corporation - International chemical workers, 40., January 28, 1965. (Box 2)
  - Vinnell Corporation - Operating engineers, 12., January 22, 1964. (Box 2)